{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following bacteria is susceptible to thiophen-2-carboxylic acid hydrazide?", "opta": "M bovis", "optb": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optc": "M chelonei", "optd": "M fortuitum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Culture of tubercle bacilli may be positive if number of bacteria in the specimen is", "opta": "as few as 1-4 per ml", "optb": "as few as 5-9 per ml", "optc": "as few as 10-100 per ml", "optd": "as few as 125-200 per ml", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Example of a Saprophytic bacteria is", "opta": "M xenopi", "optb": "Msmegmatis", "optc": "Mycobacterium chelonei", "optd": "M marinum", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Eugonic growth on Lowenstein-Jensen medium is produced by", "opta": "M bovis", "optb": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The causative agent of Buruli ulcer is", "opta": "M chelonei", "optb": "M marinum", "optc": "M fortuitum", "optd": "M ulcerarts", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "False negative Mantoux test is observed in", "opta": "early tuberculosis", "optb": "Advanced tuberculosis", "optc": "Severe malnutrition", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Humans become infected with Mycobacterium tuberculosis most frequently by", "opta": "inhalation", "optb": "ingestion", "optc": "contact", "optd": "inoculation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rough and buff colonies on LJ medium are characteristic of", "opta": "M chelonei", "optb": "M bovis", "optc": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optd": "M fortuitum", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following species of Mycobacterium is positive for nitrate reduction test?", "opta": "M chelonei", "optb": "M fortuitum", "optc": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria which is microaerophilic on primary isolation, is", "opta": "M fortuitum", "optb": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optc": "M bovis", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria is sensitive to pyrazinamide?", "opta": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optb": "M bovis", "optc": "M fortuitum", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria which cause(s) tuberculosis in man is/are", "opta": "M bovis", "optb": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "optc": "M africanum", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the phage types of Mycobacterium tuberculosis occurs most frequently in India?", "opta": "Type A", "optb": "Type B", "optc": "Type C", "optd": "Type I", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Members of the genus Mycobacterium are", "opta": "gram-positive", "optb": "acid-fast", "optc": "non-motile", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A positive Mantoux test indicates an area of induration of", "opta": "4-9 mm in diameter", "optb": "1-4 mm in diameter", "optc": "10 mm or more in diameter", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}